Hello! In this episode of Bug Bounty Reports
Explained you will learn how two hackers: Harsh
Jaiswal and Rahul Maini got a shell on not one but
three different Apple servers for which they were
rewarded $50,000. As always, the report and their
twitter profiles are linked in the description.
If you ever wondered where do I find
all those write-ups for my videos,
usually it's in Intigriti's Bug Bytes weekly
newsletter which contains the best write-ups,
tutorials, tools and videos from IT security
word. And Intigriti is a bug bounty platform
that cares about the community and they also
decided to sponsor this video. They have over
30,000 researchers and 200 active programs.
Sign up on https://go.intigriti.com/bbre
and start hacking now... well, not
literally now - first watch the video!
The hackers wanted to find a critical, well-paid
bug on Apple bug bounty program. They decided to
focus on a server called Lucee that was
found on three different apple domains.
It's a java based scripting language
that uses templates that look like this.
It's named Coldfusion and it reminds
me a bit of a PHP code. The logic is
contained inside the template file that's
rendered when the user requests this file.
Importantly, Lucee also exposes an admin
panel which is a very appealing target.
Hunters decided to run the server locally
and try to find a zero day there to then
attack the Apple server with it. It's a huge
advantage of testing an open source application.
To get the maximum impact, the vulnerability
has to be exploited without authentication.
But in .cfm files used for admin panel,
request.adminType property was checked
to see if the user is logged in as an admin.
Of course, those attempts failed at first.
But importantly, this check was not always at
the beginning of the file. That meant that all
the code above this was still executed. This is
a crucial feature. It means that if we find a
file that has a vulnerability before this check,
this can be exploited without authentication.
And finding an RCE was surprisingly easy. There
was a file imgProcess.cfm that contained this
code. It took the content from imgSrc parameter,
the filename from file parameter and saved it
inside admin-ext-thumbnails directory. .cfm
files are very powerful and, among other things,
you can create a web shell which will allow you
to execute commands on the server. But to do this,
you need to upload the .cfm file inside the
webroot. Webroot is a directory under which
files can be accessed from the web. When you want
to get an RCE by uploading a webshell, it must be
inside the webroot. Of course, by default this
imgProcess script saved files in different
directory, outside the webroot, but thankfully,
it was vulnerable to path traversal and you could
traverse back to the webroot. One problem was that
__ was added at the beginning of the filename.
It's a problem because in Linux, the path must
exist even if you traverse back from it later.
So this path will not be found because
the __ directory does not exist.
Luckily, the imgProcess.cfm has attribute
createPath=true. So first you can send such
requests so that the __ directory is created, so
then you can execute directory traversal later.
This is the request that gave you an RCE
on the local instance. But it didn't work
on Apple server. It's because of Apple web
application firewall which is very strict and
does not allow ../ characters to be present in
the URL. It successfully prevented this attack.
Hunters needed to find a bypass for that. They
found admin.index.search.cfm file which seemed
to copy files from one location to another.
This could be chained with the imgProcess.
In the first step, you would upload a
shell using imgProcess to a safe directory
without path traversal. Then, in the second step
you would copy this file inside the webroot.
Using absolute paths would allow avoiding ../
characters. But turned out it wasn't a normal
copy. It didn't even copy the file contents.
But if you had a file which name matched this
expression and contents that matched this
regex and you would upload it to a directory
pointed by this parameter, the name of this file
would be saved inside searchindex.cfm file inside
the datadir directory. The file name would be
saved inside JSON that's nested in the cfm file.
This allows you to put the CFML tags inside
the name of the file. The code inside those
tags will be executed when the searchindex.cfm
file is requested. For this, it must be placed
inside the webroot. But again, you control
the directory in which it will be saved.
Connecting all these together, you can achieve
an RCE. Let's now go through it step by step.
First, you create a file with the payload inside
its name. The content of this file doesn't matter
a lot, but it must match this regex. Then,
using imgProcess endpoint, this file will
be saved inside admin-ext-thumbnails directory,
outside the webroot. To keep the filename short,
do not put the whole webshell there. This code allows
you to upload any file which can be used to upload
the webshell later. Then, in the second step you
trigger the copy function that searches through
admin-ext-thumbnails directory and saves the name
of your file inside searchindex.cfm file which is
saved inside the webroot. Then, you request the
searchindex endpoint which lets you to upload
any file. You can upload this webshell there. In step
4, you have success - you achieved an RCE...
at least on the one host with the newer version
of Lucee. But turned out that 2/3 servers
run the older version of Lucee which doesn't
have the imgProcess file. But similar method was
used to achieve an RCE on those two hosts.
The difference was, that instead of using
imgProcess to upload the file, our hunters
used ext.applications.upload.cfm file.
Even though reaching this endpoint caused
the application to throw an exception
about no permissions, the file was
still uploaded. It was because the
code responsible for the upload was before
the permission check. It was very important
that hunters did not believe this error but
manually checked if the file was uploaded or not.
To upload a script using this endpoint, you
can use the same payload as previously but it
must be zipped and the name of the file must be
changed to .lex. Your file with payload in its
name must be inside the zip archive. Then,
to the copy function you provide this name
with the zip:// protocol and then the server
will unpack this for you. This method gave the
webshell on the remaining two hosts. The hunters
were rewarded solid $50,000 for those free RCEs.
Apple reported the issue to Lucee
maintainers and the fix they deployed
is that unauthenticated users can now only request
free endpoints. It makes this attack impossible,
unless you are an admin, but then you
can execute code anyway. And that's it.
I think this vulnerability really shows how deep
you can get when you're testing an open source
application and also, how rewarding this can be.
Thanks for everyone reading the newsletter. I saw
an open rate of about 50% where 30% is generally
considered as a very good result. I'm also getting
a lot of messages and i'm very happy that you
like it. If you are not subscribed already, make
sure to do it using the link in the description.
But for now, thank you for watching and goodbye!